Tarun Gianchandani

Greater Mumbai, India https://in.linkedin.com/in/tarungianchandani

SUMMARY

Solution- oriented professional with over 6 yrs. of diversified experience ranging from ideating strategic consulting solutions to facilitating strategic investment deals, for diverse industry clients. Consulted with management of over 20 companies carrying projects success and most clients' retention. Progressive communication skills with an ability to collaborate with others at all levels.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Strategy Consultant – Growth Advisory | Aranca | Greater Mumbai, India

02/2023 - Present

- Having worked on 10+ strategic projects so far (achieving client retention rates of up to 90% within a
 vear), while contributed to multiple project proposals for the business development support.
- Responsible for end-to-end timely handling, managing stakeholders and execution of client projects across industry verticals such as automotive, consumer retail, industrials, automation, sustainability etc.

Few notable projects: 1) Developed global market sizing model on automotive sensor technology market for a ~\$1B sensor manufacturer with implications on go-to-market and other sensor category avenue strategies 2) Developed and successfully executed a Go/No-Go strategy for a Saudi Arabian grocery retail conglomerate to assess the feasibility and potential of entering the \$3 bn Omani modern grocery retail market, resulting in two additional projects from the same client within a year, while earned the Best Project Team award.

Deputy Director (Family Business) | ML Fruit Merchant | Greater Mumbai (Temporary)

06/2020-01/2023

· Associated to manage the business temporarily due to medical emergency faced by family member

Project Strategy Consultant | Ipsos Strategy3 | Greater Mumbai, India

11/2017-05/2020

- Responsible for planning, course & coordination of activity required to effectively manage multiple
 projects across verticals such as Automotive, Real estate, Education, Oil and Gas, Healthcare, Agriculture
 etc. with most clients pertaining to Fortune 500
- Performed in-depth analyses (e.g.. market sizing, due diligence, competitive landscape mapping, financial
 performance, channel assessment, go-to- market, market entry, growth strategy etc.) using quantitative
 & qualitative ways to produce critical business insights
- Contributed in developing project proposals, status reports and regular coordination with clients
- Conducted interviews with all levels of client stakeholders to understand current market trends and identify business pain points. Trained and coordinated with interns & analysts for project executions
- Developed strategic recommendations involving near-term and long-term solutions to clients' needs based on evaluation results

<u>Key achievements</u>: 1) Managed large program with a peak team size of about 47 including external vendors 2) Bagged new subsequent project in near term from luxury automotive client, partially basis on client's acknowledgment on past delivered project

3) Led strategic project assessments for three of the world's top five oil & gas companies in India, resulting to long-term client retention and a ~25% revenue increase for the company

Associate | Valorem Advisors (Financial Services) | Greater Mumbai, India

10/2015 - 05/2016

- Handled two accounts (Pharma & IT) with execution of research and competitive analysis
- · Identify up-to-date relevant insights on industry, financials and peer group through extensive research
- Lead meetings with financial sector leads (Private equity, other buy side & sell side institutions) on a
 weekly/bi-weekly basis to ensure their thorough understanding on clients' business functions,
 fundamentals, financials, future growth strategies and strategic fund requirements
- Navigate & identify potential strategic investment deal required by client
- Associate in developing company profiles, earnings presentations, performance metrics and annual reports for investor community and senior management

Deputy Director (Family Business) | ML Fruit Merchant | Greater Mumbai, India

06/2011 - 07/2013

- Order Placing based on market trend understanding and inventory due to the goods' perishable behavior
- Understand market requirements based on consumers changing preferences. Engaged in advisory to the
 director basis on SWOT & other helpful analyses with provisions of updates & solutions for convenient
 operation and to maximize profit & market share

EDUCATION

□ PGDBM (MBA Equivalent) - University of Sunderland (London Campus), London, UK2014□ B.Com (Financial Markets) - CHM College (University of Mumbai), Greater Mumbai, India2011□ HSC (Science) - Maharashtra Board, Greater Mumbai, India2008

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Languages: English (native), Hindi (native), Sindhi (native)
- Skills: Project management, Business strategy & outlook, MS Office, Critical thinking, Solution oriented, Market understanding, Quantitative & analytical.
- Interests: Reading(history, psychology, self-development etc.), travelling, amateur cooking, photography, fitness(calisthenics & MMA), automobile enthusiast.